CHRISTINA CRUMLEY GUPTA

(816) 616-6041 · ccrumley@kcpublicschools.org

Professional Summary

Accomplished, determined, and innovative educator with over 20 years of experience in public schools and 11 years in urban high schools. Track record of raising student achievement with diverse learners in Math class-rooms. Served as head of Algebra curriculum writing, department chair, and instructional coach at Hickman Mills. Developed a new program for KCPS for future teachers. Worked with the leadership team at Success to create new programs for alternative students.

Skills

Experience

Lxperience	
Scientific Employee / PhD Student - University of Bremen	2016 - present
Develop and evaluate the next generation learning management system with Meteor	
Define a new level of software for classroom management based on an extensive nursing cur	riculum.
IT Consultant for IBM XPages and Notes Domino - We4IT GmbH Bremen	2014 - 2016
Realize projects in XPages and We4IT Aveedo, monitor project status, conduct reports	
Implement the frontend for a BPMN compatible engine within We4IT Aveedo	
Scientific Employee / Software Development - University of Bremen	2012 - 2014
Invented a flexible assessment framework, targeting industrial trainees	
Supervised software development lifecycle, Recruited team members	
Project Management Simulation Training - Getoq Consulting	2011 / 11
Performed a two-day project simulation from management perspective	
· Topics included customer contracts, change management, controlling, operational tasks	
Student Assistant / Programmer - otulea.uni-bremen.de	2010 - 2011
Realized an online diagnosis platform for workforce literacy development (Flex)	
· Modeled software design, implemented various prototypes, conducted usability tests	
Education	
Graduated as M.Sc. Digital Media - University of Bremen	2015 / 07
	2013 / 0/
· Master Thesis: Semi Automated Scoring in Technology Based Assessment · Developed and evaluated an algorithm for semi automated scoring of spreadsheet data	
Developed and evaluated an algentim not serm automated seeming of spreadsheet data	
Master Project - PrIMA - University of Bremen	2012 - 2013
· Co-Invented a touch table application for medical support, co-developed software (Java) · Formed a scrum team, mainted project dev server (Debian), surveyed target audience	

Semester Abroad - University of Melbourne

Master Studies Digital Media - University of Bremen

2009 - 2010

2012 - 2015

· Mastered six months of study and trans-cultural experience in Melbourne, Australia

· Professionalized in research methods, software development and e-assessment

· Inter-cultural classes in English, covering special topics in computer science and design

· Finished machine programming, information visualization, professional essay writing